呵呵。 呵呵。 呵呵。 吼！
Ho. Ho. Ho. Ho!
吼！ 吼！ 吼！ 吼！ 吼！
Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho!
我們是來提款的。
We're here to make a withdrawal.
呵，呵，他媽的呵。
Ho, ho, fucking ho.
聖誕老人想知道誰負責這些離譜的透支費用。
Santa wants to know who's in charge
of these outrageous overdraft fees.
把錢放在袋子裡。
Put the money in the bag.
我的朋友們，這家銀行是一個腐敗機構。
My friends, this bank is
an institution of corruption.
多好的小姑娘啊。 聖誕老人不會忘記你。
What a good little girl.
Santa won't forget you.
這就是你崇拜的東西，你的錢。
This is what you worship, your money.
這個地方只關心你的錢！ 你想傷害他們？
This place only cares about your money!
You wanna hurt them?
這就是你傷害他們的方式。
This is how you hurt them.
你拿走對他們來說珍貴的東西。
You take what's precious to them.
聖誕節快到了。
Christmas is coming.
所以，我想說，“聖誕快樂，綿羊，”
So, I wanna say,
"merry Christmas, sheep,"
因為你將拆開禮物，這是偉大的解放！
because you will unwrap a present
which is the great liberation!
並且會像啟示錄中的地震一樣毀滅這個文明！
And it will destroy this civilization
just like an earthquake
from the book of revelations!
每個人都站起來！
Everybody get up!
移動！ 向上！
Move! Up!
移動！ 我們走吧！ 移動！ 快點！ 去！ 去！ 去！
Move! Let's go! Move! Come on!
Go! Go! Go!
快他媽的起來！
Hurry the fuck up!
你讓我想起了我的母親。
You remind me of my mother.
- 我喜歡我媽媽...
- 去吧！
- I liked my mother...
- Go!
但我永遠不會原諒她把我帶到這個可怕的世界。
But I never forgave her
for bringing me into this horrible world.
因為你們一直都是好孩子，所以你們可以早點打開禮物。
Because you have been
such good boys and girls,
you can unwrap one gift early.
聖誕節快樂。
Merry Christmas.
吼！ 吼！ 吼！
Ho! Ho! Ho!
你們這些所謂的執法人員
You so-called men
of law enforcement
囚禁這個國家的人民太久了。
have imprisoned the people of this country
for far too long.
是時候了解聖誕節的真正含義了。
It's time you learn
the true meaning of Christmas.
殺光他們。
Kill them all.
我們的首要任務是幫助嫌疑人。
Our main priority is iding suspects.
我們將全力配合聯邦調查局和市長辦公室。
We'll give the FBI and the mayor's office
our full cooperation.
明白了嗎？
Understood?
媽的，我們今天被打了。
Damn, we got hit today.
而我們輸了。
And we lost.
但只要我們站起來，並且……我們記住我們的立場，我們就會永遠贏。
But as long as we are standing, and...
And we remember what we're standing for,
we will always win.
他們拿著刀來對付你，你拿著槍來對付他們。
They come at you with a knife,
you come at them with a gun.
他們拿著槍向你襲來，我會...
They come at you with a gun, I will...
我向上帝發誓，我會給你一個該死的坦克。
I swear to god, I will get you
a fucking tank.
我想看看誰乾了這狗屎受審。
I wanna see whoever did
this shit stand trial.
清楚嗎？
Are we clear?
讓我們開始工作吧。
Let's get to work.
詹姆斯愛德華騎士。
James Edward knight.
前警察。 前夫。
Ex-cop. Ex-husband.
前軍人。
Ex-military.
那是很多前任，奈特先生。
That's a lot of exes, Mr. Knight.
可以欣賞。
Can appreciate that.
- 郵件。
- 阿富汗之旅，
- Mail.
- Tour in Afghanistan,
隨後在紐瓦克和洛杉磯擔任警察。
followed by stints as a cop
in both Newark and Los Angeles.
逮捕的次數與傳票的次數一樣多。
As many arrests as you had citations.
奈特先生，您是我高級機構的客人，等待審判。
Mr. Knight, you are a guest in my fine
establishment, awaiting trial.
不會有任何特權。
There will be no special privileges.
晚上你會一個人，但白天你會和普通人在一起。
You will be alone at night,
but during the day you will be
with general population.
沒有廢話。 有7個！ 不要賭博。 不會有戰鬥。
There 'i/ be no bullshit. There 7! Be
no gambling. There will be no fighting.
我希望你每天能見到傳教士一次。
I expect you to see
the preacher once a day.
我們都是上帝的孩子，奈特先生，但這是我的房子。
We are all god's children, Mr. Knight,
but this is my house.
歡迎回家。
Welcome home.
認為你會融入其中。
Think you're gonna fit right in.
郵件。
Mail.
地區檢察官。
District attorney.
“凱西·羅茲，我們代表公設辯護人辦公室，特此請求您考慮所列的認罪協議……”
"Casey rhodes, on behalf of the public
defenders office,
we hereby ask that you consider
the plea agreement set forth..."
“二十五年監禁。”
"Twenty-five years incarceration."
全能者賜福給我們 Jaden。
The almighty
has blessed us with Jaden.
但現在他必須去行在光中。
But now he has to go
and walk in the light.
我們表示祝賀。
And we offer our congratulations.
站起來，傑登。 快點。 起床。
Stand up, Jaden.
Come on. Get up.
多謝你們。
Thanks, guys.
嘿。
Hey.
你在這裡成為一個男人，好嗎？
You became a man in here, okay?
他媽的。
Fuck.
你好，我是來自缺席父親部門的 Casey Rhodes。
Hello, this is Casey rhodes,
from the department of absentee fathers.
不不不，寶貝，我太...
No, no, no, babe, I'm so...
對不起。 我想變得有趣。
I'm sorry. I was trying to be funny.
不，等等。 嘿，快點。 給我一秒鐘。
No, wait. Hey, come on. Gimme a sec.
可以……就放……
Can... just put...
幫我一個... 讓 Clara 戴上一秒鐘。 放...
Do me a... just put Clara on
for a second. Put...
寶貝，讓克拉拉接他媽的電話。
Babe, put Clara on the fucking phone.
放...親愛的，我得到一...兩分鐘。 快點。
Put... darling, I get one... two minutes
here. Come on.
好吧，終於。
All right, finally.
好的。
All right.
開始了。
Here we go.
好的。 從這裡開始，nighty-night。
All right. Start here, nighty—night.
嗯，好的。
Mm, okay.
偵探，你的賭注。
Detective, your bet.
好吧，我會再見的。 我養你一個
All right, I'll see you.
I raise you one.
軟軟的軟軟的。
The flippity floppity.
哎呀，聖靈。
Geez, the holy ghost.
父親，最近怎麼樣？
How's it going, father?
說得好。 好好。 我可以加入你們嗎？
Well said. Good, good.
Can ijoin you guys?
滾開
Fuck off.
你們都說硬話。
You all talk tough.
你想知道什麼是艱難嗎？
You wanna know what tough is?
改變。
Change.
因為改變需要犧牲。
Because change takes sacrifice.
你必須先在這裡自由，然後才能在那裡自由。
You have to be free in here first
before you can be free out there.
是的，那個兜售宗教的人說。
Yeah, says the guy peddling religion.
我可能是一個虔誠的人，但我不是在兜售宗教。
I may be a religious man,
but I'm not selling religion.
我在賣自由。
I'm selling freedom.
羅德兄弟，你願意做什麼，才能見到你的家人，重獲自由？
Brother rhodes,
what are you willing to do
to see your family and be free again?
任何事物。
Anything.
我什麼都願意做。
I'd do anything.
你他媽的是個癮君子，凱西。
You're a fucking drug addict, Casey.
爸爸！
Daddy!
你現在在地獄裡，兄弟。
You're in hell right now, brother.
我一直在你所在的地方。
I've been right where you are.
他們把我關進監獄並扔掉了鑰匙。
They tossed me in jail
and threw away the key.
所有的痛苦。
All that pain.
所有的憤怒。
All that rage.
你不要浪費它。
Don't you waste it.
讓它淨化你，兄弟。
Let it purify you, brother.
讓它成為你的指路明燈。
Let it become your guiding star.
想想你的家人。
Think about your family.
想想你能為他們做的所有好事。
Think about all the good
you can do for them.
我保證你會像鳳凰一樣再次崛起。
And I promise you'll rise again
like a Phoenix.
比以往任何時候都偉大。
Greater than you've ever been.
我相信你，凱西羅茲。
I believe in you, Casey rhodes.
你相信自己嗎？
Do you believe in yourself?
一個自稱是真正的聖誕節聖徒的組織聲稱對紐約市的連環爆炸事件負責。
A group calling themselves
the real saints of Christmas
have claimed responsibility for the spate
of bombings across New York City.
吼！ 吼！ 吼！
Ho! Ho! Ho!
這是一種解放。
This is a liberation.
趴在地上！
Get on the ground!
趴在地上，向你最喜歡的神祈禱。
Get on the ground and pray
to your favorite god.
你們都會出名的。
You're gonna all be famous.
這是我送給你的禮物。
This is my present to you.
他媽的聖誕快樂。
Merry fucking Christmas.
偉大的解放就在眼前，而你是其​​中的一部分。
The great liberation is at hand,
and you are a part of it.
我們要走了...
We're going...
讓他們起來。 把它們放在金庫裡。
Get them up.
Get them in the vault.
有人在那些安全攝像頭上炸了一個洞。
Someone blast a hole
in those security cameras.
把他們弄進去。
Get them in there.
但我不是在兜售宗教。
But I'm not selling religion.
我在賣自由。
I'm selling freedom.
- 站起來，傑登。 快點。 起床。
- 多謝你們。
- Stand up, Jaden. Come on. Get up.
- Thanks, guys.
兄弟，求醫。
Brother, med, please.
我的視野很清晰...
My vision is clear...
進到那裡去。 移動！ 移動！ 進入金庫。
Get in there. Move! Move!
Get into the vault.
因為你的英雄氣概和忠誠，兄弟。
Because of your heroism
and your loyalty, brother.
但是我沒有多餘的空間。
But I've got no room for dead weight.
什麼……沒有人掉隊是怎麼回事？
What... what happened
to no man left behind?
他們把我們都拋在了身後。
They left us all behind.
我需要更多的男人。
I need more men.
Kravitz 博士，主廳有訪客。
Dr. Kravitz,
you have a visitor in the main hall.
什麼，你有聖誕精神？
What, you in the Christmas spirit?
你要撤銷對我搭檔的指控？
You're gonna drop the charges
on my partner?
- 是時候了。
- 他做了正確的事，隊長。
- 'Tis the season.
- He did the right thing, cap.
看，我試著給他寫信。
Look, I try and write him letters.
我試著打電話給他。 他不會跟我說話。
I try and call him.
He won't speak to me.
他不讓我告訴他...
He won't let me tell him that...
他做了每個合夥人都應該做的事，並支持我。
He did what every partner should do
and had my back.
他無視正當程序。
He ignored due process.
他褻瀆了他的誓言。
He desecrated the oath he took.
是的，奈特會稱之為美好的一天工作。
Yeah, knight would call that
a good day's work.
你在跟踪聖誕轟炸機嗎？
You following the Christmas bomber?
什麼，你要把所有這些狗屎都寄託在他身上？
What, you're gonna pin
all that shit on him too?
我沒牌可玩了。
I'm out of cards to play.
聯邦調查局、中央情報局...
FBI, CIA...
沒有人有任何線索。
Nobody has any leads.
我們進行了步態分析，分析了通過 ibis 發射的每一發砲彈。
We ran a gait analysis,
ran every shell fired through ibis.
沒有。 這傢伙是個鬼。
Nothing. This guy's a ghost.
但是奈特卻事半功倍。
But knight has done more with less.
你我都知道騎士會同意加入狩獵。
You and I both know knight would say yes
to joining the hunt.
不不不。 奈特將他的一生獻給了這份工作。
No, no, no.
Knight has dedicated his life to this job.
他失去了妻子、與孩子的關係以及自由。
He lost his wife,
his relationship with his kid,
and his freedom.
如果他抓住了轟炸機，也許他會找回那三個人中的一個。
And if he catches the bomber,
maybe he gets one of those three back.
不要為了抓住怪物而把他變成怪物。
Don't turn him into a monster
just to catch a monster.
我得到了一個害怕離開他們的房子的城市。
I got a city too scared
to leave their houses.
我有一個瘋子在聖誕節炸毀了銀行。
I got a madman blowing up banks
on Christmas.
我有一位市長……沒關係。
And I got a mayor that...
Never mind.
不不不。 說完那句話。
No, no, no. Finish that sentence.
- 什麼……市長呢？
- 忘了我說的關於市長的話。
- What... what about the mayor?
- Forget what I said about the mayor.
你甚至都不想來紐約。
And don't you even think
about coming to New York.
神父... 是什麼讓你來到這裡？
Padre...
What brings you down here?
- 你好，典獄長。 你晚上過得怎麼樣？
- 糟糕的。
- Hi, warden. How's your night going?
- Terrible.
看起來它比你的視野更好？
Seems like it's a damn sight
better than yours?
你非常直覺。 是的。
You're very intuitive. Yeah.
我不知道這個晚上我在這裡做什麼，我知道這是一個錯誤。
I don't know what I'm doing out here
this time of night, I know it's a mistake.
我做了一個夢。
I had a dream.
是的，關於男生。
Yeah, about the guys.
關於監獄裡的一些人。 我曾是...
About some of the men in prison. I was...
我只是想檢查一下，確保他們沒事。
I just wanna check on them,
make sure they're okay.
你有夢想嗎？ 像是……像是一種預感？
You had a dream?
Like a... like a premonition?
就像一個……像一個幻象。
Like a... like a vision.
那麼，我們夢見什麼樣的囚犯呢？
So, what prisoner
are we dreaming about?
所有的人。
All of 'em.
- 他們全部？
- 是的。
- All of them?
- Yeah.
是的，我知道這是一個錯誤。 我...
Yeah, I know this was a mistake. I...
如果他們看到我在這裡，他們會認為有什麼地方不對勁。
If they see me out here,
they're gonna think something's amiss.
那會創造出各種各樣的戲劇。 我不想要那個。
That's gonna create all kinds of drama.
I didn't want that.
我想你就在那裡。 我想你是對的。
I think you're right there.
I think you're right.
- 是的。 不
- 等一下 等一下。
- Yeah. No.
- Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
安全中心。
The security center.
我可以通過監視器查看。
I could look through the monitors.
他們不會看到我。 這會讓我放心。
They wouldn't see me.
It would set my mind at ease.
- 我會感覺好多了。
- 不。
- I would feel so much better.
- No.
是啊是啊。 你是對的。
Yeah, yeah. You're right.
- 是的？
- 快點。 今天是聖誕節。
- Yeah?
- Come on. It's Christmas.
我們來看看，好嗎？
Let's take a look, shall we?
- 好的。
- 是的。 讓我們來看看。
- Okay.
- Yeah. Let's take a look.
- 你是個好人。
- 我知道。
- You're a good man.
- I know.
所有存在和占。
All present and accounted for.
當然是。
Of course they are.
我經營的船比納爾遜勳爵做過的還要嚴格。
I run a tighter ship
than lord Nelson ever did.
現在，康蘭神父，你的願景是什麼？
Now, father conlan,
what was your vision?
哦，我預見了你的死亡。
Oh, I envisioned your death.
我可以引起你的注意嗎，我的兄弟們？
Can I have your attention,
my brothers?
我給你帶來了很棒的聖誕消息。
I bring you great Christmas tidings.
今天是解放的開始。
Today is the beginning
of the liberation.
所以準備好自己。
So prepare yourselves.
唔。
Hmm.
讓它開始。
Let it begin.
羅德兄弟，你在哪裡？
Where are you, brother rhodes?
嗨，老兄。
Hey, man.
你沒事吧？
You all right?
是啊是啊。 是的。
Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
對你來說，這一天誕生了救世主。
And unto you,
this day was born a savior.
罪的工價就是死。
And the wages of sin is death.
自由是一份禮物。
And freedom is a gift.
你監禁了你的兄弟，這是不被...任何其他物種遵守的。
You have incarcerated your brothers,
which is not abided by...
By any other species.
所以今天，
So today,
我把自由的禮物給我的兄弟們。
I give the gift of freedom to my brothers.
因為自由是他們與生俱來的權利。
Because freedom is their birthright.
自由是我們將要擁有的。
Freedom is what we will take.
聖誕快樂，混蛋！
Merry Christmas, motherfuckers!
吼！ 吼！ 吼！
Ho! Ho! Ho!
今晚，5 名警衛被確認死亡，42
Five guards are confirmed dead
名罪犯從紐約賴克斯最高安全監獄逃脫。
and 42 convicts escaped from New York's
rikers maximum security prison tonight.
警方公佈了其中一名嫌疑人的描述。
The police have released a description
of one of the suspects.
瑞奇·康蘭 (Ricky
Ricky conlan, a former marine
turned prison chaplain,
conlan)，一名前海軍陸戰隊員轉為監獄牧師，現在也正在接受訊問
who is also now being sought
for questioning
關於對城市銀行的聖誕節爆炸襲擊。
regarding the Christmas bombing attacks
on the city's banks.
- 我們元帥已經被派遣...
- 你可以離開了
- Us marshals have been dispatched...
- You can leave.
我以為你會和其他人分開。
I thought you'd split
with the rest of 'em.
一張好床，呃……很難找。
A good bed is, uh... is hard to find.
我需要你閱讀嫌疑人的資料。
I need your read on a suspect.
告訴我從匡蒂科到佩里營地的每個警察和側寫員都沒有看到什麼。
Tell me what every cop and profiler
from Quantico to camp Perry isn't seeing.
他的真名是理查德“瑞奇”康蘭。
His real name is Richard "Ricky" conlan.
康蘭是特種部隊。 然後他就出軌了。
Conlan was special ops.
Then he went rogue.
他和他的同事打架，被法庭審判，
He fought with his co,
got court-man'ialed,
在 supermax 中被判處七年徒刑。
sentenced to seven years in supermax.
在裡面，康蘭的兒子陣亡，他被拒絕參加葬禮。
While inside, conlan's son
was killed in action
and he was refused permission
to attend the funeral.
在那裡的某個地方，他發現了他的精神面。
Somewhere in there,
he discovered his spiritual side.
十年前就出來了。
Got out ten years ago.
從那以後，康蘭一直擔任監獄顧問。
Ever since, conlan's been working
as a prison counselor.
我們交談過的每個人都說他是社區的支柱。
Everyone we speak to says
he's a pillar of the community.
自羅傑斯先生以來最好的事情。
Best thing since Mr. Rogers.
既然他已經被查出身份，聯邦調查局就以 21
Now that he's been ID'ed,
FBI like him for 21 homicides,
起殺人案、8 起持械搶劫銀行案為由對他下了手。
eight armed bank robberies.
在昨晚之前他從未露面，當他擊敗你的好朋友時，凱西羅茲，
Never showed his face before last night,
when he busted out your bestie,
Casey rhodes,
和其他鐵桿墮落。
and other hardcore degenerates.
你為什麼不爆發？
Why didn't you break out?
我在這裡浪費時間。
I'm wasting my time here.
每當我遇到棘手的案子時，我都會提醒自己一件事。
Whenever I had a tough case,
I'd remind myself one thing.
什麼？
What?
- 每個人都會流血。
- 你不能說那樣的廢話。
- Everyone bleeds.
- You can't be saying shit like that.
你即將因謀殺兩名嫌疑人而受審。
You are about to stand trial
for the murder of two suspects.
我殺了兩個以上。
I killed more than two.
好吧，這不是什麼值得驕傲的事情。
Okay, that is not something
to be proud of.
我殺了幾個壞人。
I killed some bad guys.
這是一個美好的一天。
It was a good day.
每個人都有權享受正當程序。 你發誓要服務和保護。
Everyone has a right to due process.
You swore an oath to serve and protect.
我擁有我所做的。
I own what I did.
你是一個恥辱。 你是一個義務警員。 你為什麼不爆發？
You're a disgrace. You're a vigilante.
Why didn't you break out?
我是警察。
I'm a cop.
這就是我的接線方式。
It's how I'm wired.
我相信法治。
I believe in the rule of the law.
你不是警察。
You are not a cop.
你是一個有徽章的罪犯，並認為這讓他有權為所欲為。
You are a criminal who had a badge
and thought it gave him the right to do
whatever the hell he wanted.
我需要你的幫助。
I need your help.
我需要你再假裝一次警察。
I need you to pretend
to be a cop one more time.
我不喜歡你。
I don't like you.
我不尊重你。
I don't respect you.
但是你可以做我做不到的事情。
But you can do things I cannot do.
在另一種生活中，
In another life,
康蘭就是你
conlan is you.
動力，自以為是。
The drive, the self-righteousness.
阻止 Ricky conlan，da 將撤銷對你的所有指控。
Stop Ricky conlan
and the da will drop
all charges against you.
- 為什麼是我？
-因為你可能已經爆發了
- Why me?
- 'Cause you could have broke out
和你牢房裡的其他人在一起，而你選擇不這樣做。
with the rest of the guys
in your cellblock and you chose not to.
你選擇了做正確的事。
You chose to do the right thing.
你並不比你殺死或關押的人好，但你仍然有優點。
You're no better
than the guys you killed or locked up,
but there's still good in you.
而且因為你是我認識的唯一一個可能比 Ricky 更瘋狂的人。
And because you're the only guy I know
who might be crazier than Ricky is.
我感到受寵若驚。
I am flattered.
但是明白這一點。
But understand this.
他不是在搶銀行。 他正在表演。
He's not robbing banks.
He's putting on a show.
你怎麼知道？
How do you know that?
像罪犯一樣思考。 它跟踪。
Think like a criminal. It tracks.
有線索嗎？
Any leads?
想听個惡趣味的笑話嗎？
Wanna hear a bad joke?
總是。
Always.
當市中心的最後一家銀行遭到襲擊時，
When the last bank was hit in midtown,
有人同時約了經理，但沒有出現。
someone had an appointment
with the manager at the same time
and didn't show.
- 猜猜是誰。
- 教皇？
- Guess who it was.
- The pope?
關閉。
Close.
- 瓦塞蒂。
- 市長。
- Vassetti.
- The mayor.
僅有的一個。
One and only.
有人告密了他。
Someone tipped him off.
告訴我我沒有做出我一生中最糟糕的決定。
Tell me I'm not making
the worst decision of my life.
我想抓住這個人
I wanna catch this guy.
把槍給我，剩下的交給我。
Give me my gun,
and I'll do the rest.
康蘭活著來找我。 知道了？
Conlan comes to me alive. Got it?
詹姆斯·奈特與一名精神錯亂的銀行劫匪。
James knight
versus a psychotic bank robber.
讓我們希望這座城市在聖誕節早晨仍然屹立不倒。
Let's hope the city's still standing
come Christmas morning.
他看起來很有趣。
He seems like a lot of fun.
他可能是噴氣機迷。
He's probably a jets fan.
看，我並不是真的喜歡這種邪教。 讓我們他媽的離開這裡。
Look, I'm not really into this cult shit.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
兄弟們，奠酒怎麼樣？
How are the libations, my brothers?
我們走吧。
Let's go.
聽他說完就走？
Hear what he has to say and leave?
當那個人說話時，你聽。
When that man speaks, you listen.
Dajon 像狗一樣吠叫，但他是一個忠誠的人。
Dajon barks like a dog,
but he's a loyal one.
我的兄弟們...
My brothers...
偉大解放的時刻到了。
The time is upon us
for the great liberation.
但我請你幫個小忙。
But I ask you one small favor.
我請你相信。
I ask you to trust.
相信我們可以一起改變世界。
Trust that together
we can change the world.
相信，當我們作為一個整體行動時，那裡的那些綿羊會在看到我們時害怕得發抖。
Trust that, when we move as one,
that those sheep out there
will tremble in fear at the sight of us.
這個國家入獄的人數比地球上任何其他國家都多。
There are more people in prison
in this country
than any other nation on the planet.
百分之七十四的靈魂在籠子裡
Seventy-four percent of souls in cages
甚至沒有被定罪。
haven't even been convicted
of a crime.
他們被關在那裡是因為他們付不起保釋金。
They're in there
because they can't afford to pay bail.
他們甚至無法支付抵押貸款和房租，而他們在豪宅中的兄弟們則嘲笑他們。
They can't even pay
their mortgage, their rent,
while their brothers
in their mansions laugh at them.
我們在迫害窮人。
We're persecuting the poor.
這讓我熱血沸騰。
It makes my blood boil.
我是這個國家的士兵。
And I was a soldier for this country.
我在你甚至在地圖上找不到的國家灑了血。
I spilled blood in countries
you can't even find on a map.
他們要我處死不該死的人。
They asked me to execute people
who did not deserve to die.
當我反對他們時，他們也把我關在籠子裡。
And when I stood against them,
they threw me in a cage too.
是的，他們確實。
Yes, they did.
然後，當我兒子在戰鬥中陣亡時……
And then, when my son died in combat...
我什至無法看到自己兒子的屍體被埋入地下。
I couldn't even see my own son's body
be lowered into the ground.
告訴我這並不殘忍。
Tell me that's not cruel.
告訴我那不是折磨。
Tell me that's not torture.
這個病態文明的腐敗...
The corruption of this sick
and diseased civilization...
我們必須消滅它。
We have to wipe it out.
我們必須將他們病態的自尊心燒毀，讓整個國家振作起來，重新開始。
We have to burn their sick egos
to the ground
and raise this whole country
and start fresh and anew.
看看這個假期。
Look at this holiday.
聖誕節。
Christmas.
他們把這個假期搞砸了。
They've perverted this holiday.
他們把它變成了一個巨大的消費主義購物中心。
They've turned it into a giant mall
of consumerism.
我們必須收回它。 我們必須把它變成我們的。
We have to take it back.
We have to make it ours.
這個幸福的日子將不再被他們的醜陋所腐蝕。
This blessed day will no longer
be corrupted by their ugliness.
我們將帶來這種改變。
We will bring that change.
因為這是戰爭。 而且不會有囚犯。
Because this is war.
And there will be no prisoners.
當他們想到聖誕節時...
And when they think of Christmas...
他們會想到我們的。
They will think of us.
但是你們當中那些不想為了這個偉大的解放而來到這裡的人……
But those of you who do not want
to be here for this great liberation...
有門。
There's the door.
沒有冒犯，沒有不敬，但是，呃，是的，伙計們，我出去了。
費利斯納維達。
No offense, no disrespect, but, uh, yeah,
fellas, I'm out. Feliz navidad.
貓。
Pussy.
不不不。 不，達容。
No, no, no. No, dajon.
那個人想要自由。
That man wants to be free.
我們給他的禮物是他的自由。
And our gift to him is his freedom.
只要確保他找到正確的出路。
Just make sure he finds the right way out.
今晚慶祝吧，我的兄弟們。
Celebrate tonight, my brothers.
明天，我們開始。
Tomorrow, we begin.
羅德兄弟。
Brother rhodes.
你沒有喝酒。
You're not drinking.
不，不，我是，呃...
No. No, I'm, uh...
你知道的，我不渴，所以...
You know, I'm not thirsty, so...
別騙我。
Don't lie to me.
不要對我撒謊，也不要為任何人掩飾。
Don't lie to me
and don't ever cover for anyone.
呃，父親，呃……
Uh, father, uh...
- 咳咳。 請你幫個忙。
- 不。
- Ahem. A favor to ask you.
- No.
甚至不知道我要問你什麼。
Don't even know
what I'm gonna ask you.
你想打電話給你的家人，告訴他們你沒事。
You wanna call your family
and tell them you're okay.
如果我和你做交易呢？
What if I make a trade with you?
你已經意識到你不僅僅是你的癮。
You've realized you're more
than your addiction.
非常好。
Very good.
快一點。
Make it quick.
很好的演講。
Nice speech.
你會在鞦韆上度過美好的一天。 會很有趣的。
You'll have a nice day on the swings.
It's gonna be so fun.
聽著，別跟著我們了，好嗎？ 我不知道凱西在哪裡。
Look, stop following us, okay?
I don't know where Casey is.
- 呃。 對不起，親愛的。
- 沒關係。
- Ugh. I'm sorry, honey.
- It's okay.
你還好嗎？
Are you okay?
- 是的。
- 是的？
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- 好吧，我做了一個噩夢。
- 是的？
- Well, I had a nightmare.
- Yeah?
爸爸再也沒有回家，因為他溺水了。
Daddy never came home
because he was drowning.
我試圖救他，但我不能。
I tried to save him, but I couldn't.
對不起，親愛的。
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
- 我可以給他打電話嗎？
- 今天不行。
- Can I call him?
- Not today.
這個家庭不會因為爸爸而哭泣。
There'll be no crying
in this household over daddy.
好的？
Okay?
- 好的。
- 好的？
- Okay.
- Okay?
媽媽正在接電話。 但是去……去玩吧。
Mommy is getting a phone call.
But go... go play.
好的。
Okay.
你好？
Hello?
您好，這裡是缺席父親部門。
Hello, this is from the
department of absentee fathers.
又來電了
Calling again.
嗨，媽媽。
Hi, mom.
你他媽的在做什麼？
What the fuck are you doing?
你過得還好吧？
How are you holding up?
嗯嗯。
Nmgmm.
她過的好嗎？
How is she doing?
她很困惑。
She's confused.
每天都有更多的問題，想知道她爸爸在哪裡，為什麼我不讓她看電視。
More questions every day,
wondering where her dad is,
and why I don't let her watch the TV.
聽著，請不要告訴我你是...你是越獄的一部分。
Look, please don't tell me that you're...
You're part of the jailbreak.
親愛的，我，呃，有點混淆了。
I, uh, kind of got mixed up in it,
darling.
我不知道它是怎麼發生的，
I don't know how it happened,
我不能在那個牢房裡多待一天。
I couldn't spend
another day in that cell.
你怎麼可以這麼傻？
How could you be so stupid?
到目前為止，幾乎用盡了所有愚蠢的東西，是吧？
Pretty much used up all the stupid
getting this far, huh?
他們說策劃越獄的人是...
They say the guy who orchestrated
the jailbreak is...
是聖誕轟炸機。
Is the Christmas bomber.
老實說，我寧願你在裡面活著，也不願...
Honestly, I'd rather you be
inside and alive than...
而不是什麼？ 死的？
Instead of what? Dead?
裡面幾乎是一模一樣的東西。
Inside is pretty much
the same exact thing.
呃，上帝。
Ugh, god.
我只是覺得你不……你不思考。
I just feel like you don't...
You don't think.
你根本不去想。 你他媽的不認為。
You don't think at all.
You don't fucking think.
- 不，我可以解決這個問題，親愛的。
- 不，你不能。
- No, I can fix this, darling.
- No, you can't.
你不能他媽的解決這個問題。
You can't fucking fix this.
- 你聽起來像個癮君子。
- 我現在和康蘭在一起，好嗎？
- You sound like an addict.
- I'm with conlan right now, okay?
我也許可以達成協議。
I can maybe cut a deal.
I need you to call the police,
我需要你報警，告訴他們我剛才告訴你的，好嗎？
tell them what I just told you, okay?
我現在就把地址發短信給你。
I'm gonna text you
the address right now.
不要放棄我，好嗎？
Don't give up on me, okay?
我愛你。
I love you.
證明給我看。
Prove it.
凱西羅茲。
Casey rhodes.
我們對你寄予厚望。
We had such high hopes for you.
什麼？
What?
讓她通過。
Put her through.
羅德夫人，有什麼可以為您效勞的嗎？
Mrs. Rhodes,
what can I do for you?
凱西打電話給我。 他和轟炸機在一起。
Casey called me.
He's with the bomber.
你什麼時候跟他說話的？
When did you talk to him?
- 現在。
- 他給你地址了嗎？
- Just now.
- Did he give you an address?
看，[需要你的話，對凱西的所有指控都將被撤銷。
Look, [need your word that all
the charges against Casey will be dropped.
- 完全免疫。
- 我可以自信地說
- Full immunity.
- I can say with confidence
市長和 da 辦公室願意達成協議。
that the mayor and the da's office
would be willing to cut a deal.
寫信給我，我會把地址發給你。
Send me something in writing,
and I'll send you the address.
天啊。
Oh, god.
拿住！ 把它放在那裡！
Hold it! Hold it right there!
這是他的b隊。
This was his b team.
康蘭在我們出現前 20 分鍾離開了。
Conlan left 20 minutes
before we showed up.
他可能被舉報了。
He might have been tipped off.
我為你冒了險。
I put my ass
on the line for you.
我讓你出去是為了得到結果。
I got you out to get results.
他的團隊在這裡準備。
His team prepped here.
他們付了現金。
They paid cash.
房東不知道。 沒有任何。
The landlord has no idea. None.
他們不知道他在哪裡。
They don't know where he is.
康蘭總是領先一步。
Conlan is always one step ahead.
- 聯邦調查局有什麼嗎？
- 他們知道的比我們少。
- Do the feds have anything?
- They know less than we do.
只有一名證人我們沒有詢問過。
There's only one witness
that we haven't questioned.
我們不能讓市長介入。
We cannot get the mayor involved.
你說要不惜一切代價。
You said to do whatever it takes.
這就是它所需要的。
This is what it takes.
好吧，我會...
All right, I'll...
- 我會見他，好嗎？
- 你是個好人，船長。
- I'll meet with him, okay?
- You're a good one, captain.
難道我不知道嗎。
Don't I know it.
嘿，我兒子拉大提琴。
Hey, my son plays the cello.
是的，你很擅長。
Yeah, you're pretty good at it.
不，不，不要……請不要停下來。
No, no, don't... don't stop, please.
你試試玩四個小時。
You try playing for four hours.
- 呃，那將是一個艱難的過程。
- 確切地。
- Uh, that'll be a hard pass.
- Exactly.
你是警察？
You a cop?
為什麼？
Why?
去他媽的警察。
Fuck the police.
迷人。
Charming.
亞瑟，我們需要討論一下你昨晚在哪裡。
Arthur, we need to discuss
where you were last night.
我們得談談。
We're gonna have
to have a conversation.
歡迎來到我家，先生。
Welcome to my home, sir.
任何想向這座城市捐款的人都是我的朋友。
Anyone thinking of donating to the city,
well, is a friend of mine.
啊，是的。
Ah, yeah.
是的，那只是個謊言，所以我可以在更短的通知時間內與您預約。
Yeah, that was just a lie,
so I was able to get an appointment
with you on shorter notice.
我什至不是選民。
I'm not even a constituent.
你知道，我絕對不會投票給你。
You know, and I definitely
wouldn't vote for you.
但我確實有這個。
But I do have this.
洛杉磯。
Los Angeles.
你不在你的管轄範圍內，你在浪費我的時間。
You're out of your jurisdiction
and you're wasting my time.
而你卻讓一個瘋子炸毀了銀行。
And you're letting
a madman blow up banks.
所以我想你和我有很多話要談。
So I guess you and I
have a lot to talk about.
伙計，我希望我能在你每週的撲克比賽中佔有一席之地，因為你撒謊。
Man, I wish I had a seat
at your weekly poker game,
because you lie for shit.
現在，為什麼你在銀行破產的那天錯過了你在銀行的約會？
Now, why did you miss
your appointment at the bank
the day that it was blowing up?
中城交通。
Midtown traffic.
預約的目的是什麼？
What was the appointment for?
唔？ 什麼，你需要貸款？
Hmm? What, you need a loan?
我是，呃，想關閉我的保險箱。
I was, uh, looking to close out
my safety deposit box.
瑞奇·康蘭 (Ricky conlan) 打敗了您。
And Ricky conlan beat you to it.
唔。 裡面有什麼？
Hmm. What was in it?
- 沒什麼重要的。
- 快點。
- Nothing of importance.
- Come on.
沒有血鑽？
No blood diamonds?
沒有你穿小白袍戴尖頭帽的照片嗎？
No photos of you in a little white robe
with a little pointy hat?
不。
No.
快點。 康蘭對你有什麼看法，是嗎？
Come on. What does conlan have
on you, huh?
你操女僕的視頻？
Video of you fucking the maid?
亞瑟？
Arthur?
再來一次。
Again, please.
真是可愛的孩子。
Really sweet kid.
好吧，我需要為我的新聞發布會做準備。
Well, I need to prepare
for my press conference.
當然。 你得排練所有那些廢話。
Of course. You gotta rehearse
all that bullshit.
謝謝你的服務，軍官。
Thank you for your service, officer.
其實就是“偵探”。
Actually, that's "detective."
很抱歉我幫不上什麼忙。
I'm sorry I couldn't be more help.
哦，別抱歉。
Oh, don't be sorry.
不，你幫了大忙。
No, you were a great deal of help.
在你之後。
After you.
哦，你知道嗎？
Oh, you know what?
不，啊，只有，嗯……
No, ah, there's just, um...
- 我還有一件事。  - 嗯嗯。
- I just have one more thing.
- Mm-hmm.
你還有保險箱嗎？
Do you still have safety deposit boxes?
現在，你為什麼想知道那個？
Now, why would you want to know that?
啊，康蘭搶劫之後，你把他們搬到哪裡去了？
Ah, just after conlan's heist,
where did you move them to?
我將它們合併到一個位置。
I consolidated them into one location.
那會在哪裡？
And where would that be?
堅不可摧的銀行。
An impenetrable bank.
很少有人知道實際位置。
Few know the actual location.
- 將其視為 1% 的諾克斯堡。
- 啊。
- Consider it a fort Knox for the 1%.
- Ah.
好吧，市長先生，我想你和我會經常見面。
Well, Mr. Mayor, I think that you and I
are gonna be seeing a lot of each other.
- 我很喜歡它。
- 好的。
- I look fonlvard to it.
- Good.
哦，還有，市長先生，您的手腕尺寸是多少？
Oh, and, uh,
what's your wrist size, Mr. Mayor?
我很樂意在聖誕節送你一副漂亮的毛茸茸的小手銬。
I'd love to send you a nice little fuzzy
pair of handcuffs for Christmas.
- 您可以保留行程。
- 吹我。
- You can keep the itinerary.
- Blow me.
什麼...
What the...
你怎麼進來的？
How'd you get in here?
好吧，那是在我和門之間。
Well, that's between me
and the door.
從我的辦公桌後面滾出去。 我問你一個問題...哦。
Get out from behind my desk.
I asked you a ques... oh.
你坐在輪椅上。
You're in a wheelchair.
子彈沒有擊中我的脊椎，所以如果我站穩腳跟，
Bullets didn't hit my spine,
so if I stay off my feet,
我將在陣亡將士紀念日之前啟動並運行。
I'll be up and running by Memorial Day.
你到底是怎麼進來的？
How the hell did you get in here?
是的，好吧，你是個偵探。 你想通了。
Yeah, well, you're a detective.
You figure it out.
你從洛杉磯一路飛到紐約闖進我的辦公室？
You flew all the way from la to New York
to bust into my office?
哦，我現在不妨告訴你，因為你會發現的。
Oh, and I might as well tell you now,
because you will find out.
我拜訪了市長。
I paid a visit to the mayor.
伙計，我簡直不敢相信...
Man, I can't believe...
他真是個糟糕的說謊者。 到目前為止，他在政治上取得了成功。
He's such a bad liar.
He's made it so far in politics.
現在他正在給我發消息，問我為什麼一些洛杉磯警察要問他問題。
Now he's messaging me,
asking me why some L.A. cop
is asking him questions.
因為他參與了。
Because he's involved.
這可能是這座城市歷史上最大的醜聞。
This could be the biggest scandal
in the history of the city.
我知道康蘭對市長有所了解。
I know conlan's got
something on the mayor.
讓我們只希望如果騎士發現它是什麼，他會做正確的事。
Let's just hope if knight finds out
what it is, he'll do the right thing.
是的，騎士會遵守規則。
Yeah, knight will play by the book.
我有一種感覺，他對“循規蹈矩”的定義
I have a feeling his definition
of "by the book"
就是用一本書打死一個人。
is to beat a guy to death with a book.
- 在 conlan 上找到任何東西？
- 不。
- Find anything on conlan?
- No.
他想擺脫金錢世界，但他卻在扮演聖誕老人。
He wants to rid the world of money,
yet he is playing Santa claus.
他做一套，說一套。
He does one thing, says another.
我認為他想讓世界相信他是一隻動物。
I think that he wants the world
to believe he's an animal.
所以找出誰在牽著皮帶。
So find out who's holding the leash.
是的女士。
Yes, ma'am.
第一個問題是，我的伙伴在哪裡？
The first question is,
where is my partner?
你是一名偵探。 想辦法。
You're a detective. Figure it out.
謝謝大家的光臨。
Thank you all for coming.
我要通知 Ricky conlan。
I am putting Ricky conlan on notice.
我們會逮捕你。
We will apprehend you.
我還通知了警察局和船長 Anna Shea。
I am also putting the police department
and captain Anna shea on notice.
如果你的指令失敗，我會來找你。
I will come after you
if you fail in your directive.
吼！ 吼！
Ho! Ho!
瑞奇康蘭不是某種羅賓漢。
Ricky conlan is not
some sort of Robin hood.
下來！
Get down!
他媽的聖誕快樂！
Merry fucking Christmas!
眼睛在地上。
Eyes on the ground.
你明白問題所在嗎？
You understand the problem?
你想看看我的臉嗎？ 看著我，混蛋！
You wanna see my face?
Look at me, motherfucker!
別動！
Don't move!
我想要我的禮物！
I want my present!
他是最低級的罪犯。
He's a criminal of the lowest kind.
我是來救你的！
I am here to save you!
看看你崇拜的這個神。 起來！
Look at this god you worship. Stand up!
這不是聖誕節！
This is not Christmas!
你想一輩子拜金？
You wanna worship money your whole life?
當你在地獄時，你會看到它花得多麼好。
You see how well it spends
when you're in hell.
等等，不。 我有一個家庭。
Wait, no. I have a family.
我們走吧。
Let's go.
我敦促您不要相信他的號召，而將其視為掩蓋他的犯罪活動的煙幕。
I urge you not to buy
into his call to arms,
and see it as nothing but a smokescreen
to hide his criminal activity.
他正在招募有前科的人。
He is recruiting ex-convicts.
- 他想給他們洗腦...
- 聖誕快樂
- He is attempting to brainwash them...
- Merry Christmas.
這樣他們就可以加入他的事業。
So they can join his cause.
如果發現有人在幫助瑞奇·康蘭，你會感受到這座城市的全部力量都壓在了你的頭上。
If there is anyone found
aiding Ricky conlan,
you will feel the full force of this city
brought to bear upon your heads.
現在，如果你有任何問題，
Now, if you have any questions,
問船長 Anna Shea，看看她會給你什麼答案。 謝謝你。
ask captain Anna shea
and see what answers
she gives you. Thank you.
混蛋！
Motherfucker!
你想出賣我們？
You wanna sell us out?
出賣康蘭這樣的偉人？
Sell out a great man like conlan?
我聽說你叫你的球鏈，混蛋。
I heard you call your ball and chain,
motherfucker.
你他媽有毛病？
The fuck is wrong with you?
哦，這是一個長長的名單，兄弟。
Oh, it's a long list, brother.
他本可以為你做他為我做的事。
He could have done for you
what he did for me.
他把我從街上帶走，給了我目標，讓我變得真實。
He took me from the streets
and gave me purpose, made me real.
失望是一件很糟糕的事情。
Disappointment is a hell of a thing.
對別人做...
Do unto others...
正如你希望他們對你做的那樣。
As you would have them do unto you.
你想讓他們把我像狗一樣射下來。
You wanted them
to shoot me down like a dog.
- 不
- 你為什麼要達成協議？
- No.
- Why did you try to cut a deal?
來吧，你要燒掉我的屁股來拯救你的，不是嗎？
Come on, you were gonna burn my ass
to save yours, weren't you?
不不不。 那不是什麼...
No, no, no. That's not what...
- 你別騙我。
- 好的。
- Don't you lie to me.
- Okay.
好的。 我可能是個騙子，但我他媽的沒瘋。
Yeah, okay. I may be a liar,
but I'm not fucking crazy.
好吧，在這樣的社會裡，發瘋可能是一件美好的事情。
Well, in a society like this,
being crazy could be a beautiful thing.
你懂？
You know?
所以讓我再問你一次。
So let me ask you one more time.
你有沒有試著達成協議
Did you try to cut a deal
- 紐約養豬部門？
- F...
- with the New York pig department?
我所要求的只是真相。
All I'm asking for is the truth.
我只想要真相，兒子。
All I want, just the truth, son.
就他媽的殺了我，伙計。 讓我們結束吧。
Just fucking kill me, man.
Let's get it over with.
不，不，不，不，不，不，不。 你不明白。
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
You don't understand.
你沒有……這不是你的錯。
You don't under... this is not your fault.
不，不。 這……這是騙子大騙局的一部分。
No, no. Th... this is part
of the great deception of the liars.
他們利用你就像利用我一樣。
They used you just like they used me.
你難道不懂嗎？
Don't you see?
他們用所有的……輝煌，黃金，還有……還有……還有……分散了我們的注意力
They distracted us
with all the... the splendor,
and the gold, and the...
And the... and the...
還有盛大的場面。 正確的？
And the pageantry
and the theatrics. Right?
“你做得很好，兒子。
"You're doing such a good job, son.
為你的國家服務做得很好。”
Well done servicing your country."
正確的？ 愛國主義，仇外心理。
Right? Patriotism, xenophobia.
他們將這種沙文主義充斥在我們的腦海中，然後帶我們走出去。
This jingoism they filled in our heads,
and they walked us out there.
他們給了你...
And they gave you...
他們給了你一張豬皮。
They gave you a pigskin.
他們說，“你把它從戰場的一端帶到另一端。”
And they said, "you carry it from one end
of the battlefield to the other."
他們遞給我一支步槍，教我如何殺人。
And they handed me a rifle,
and they taught me how to kill.
他知道事情，伙計。 他是一個說真話的人。
He knows things, man.
He's a truth teller.
嘿，操你媽的。
Hey, fuck you.
不，不，不要生他的氣。 快點。
No, no, don't be angry at him.
Come on.
你對讓你在沒有理由相信的情況下被遺棄在貧困和解體的海岸上的製度感到憤怒。
You're angry at the system
that left you deserted
on the shores of poverty and dissolution
without a cause to believe in.
但我已經修好了。
But I've got that fixed.
因為你和我是一樣的。 我們都來自同一個社會。
'Cause you and I are the same.
We're both from the same society.
我們在這裡沒有做錯任何事。 我們不是罪犯。
We didn't do anything wrong here.
We're not criminals.
我們是自己故事中的主角。
We're protagonists in our own story.
當然，伙計。 是的。
Sure, man. Yeah.
我明白了，這是有道理的。 當然，這是有道理的。
I get it, that makes sense.
That makes sense, sure.
我想要真相。
I want the truth.
你的信念還不足以讓你進入下一章，我的孩子。
Your faith isn't strong enough to get you
to the next chapter, my son.
我必須讓你做出選擇。
I got to make you make a choice.
我真的很討厭這樣做，但我必須給你看一些東西。
I really hate doing this,
but I have to show you something.
這很好。 這有點糟糕。
It's good. It's kind of bad.
但總有一天，我保證，你會為此感謝我的。
But one day, I promise,
you're gonna thank me for it.
不不不不！ 去你的！
No. No, no, no! Fuck you!
不！
No!
不，不，我試過……我試過操你，好嗎？
No, no, I tried...
I tried to fuck you, okay?
我是個廢物，好嗎？
I'm a piece of shit, okay?
我……我是個癮君子。 讓他們走吧。
I'm... I'm a drug addict.
Just let them go.
去你的！ 讓他們去吧！ 去你的！ 讓他們去吧！
Fuck you! Let them go!
噓。
Shh.
給你。
There you go.
給你。 看著我。
There you go. Look at me.
看著我。 看著我。
Look at me. Look at me.
好的，好的，好的。
Okay, okay, okay.
那就是精神。
That's the spirit.
但是你開槍打我，他們都死了。
But you shoot me, they all die.
好的？ 你自己開槍，他們都死了。
Okay? You shoot yourself, they all die.
好吧，你現在必須做出選擇。
Okay, you have to make a choice now.
你必須做出選擇，這樣你才能自由。
You have to make a choice
so you can be free.
選擇是什麼？
What's the choice?
- 帶他進來
- 什麼？
- Bring him in.
- What?
現在做出決定，讓自己自由。
Now make a decision
and set yourself free.
- 啊，他媽的。
- 哦，這是你的兄弟。
- Ah, fuck.
- Oh, it's your brother.
他不是其中的一部分。 這就是我。
He wasn't part of this. This is me.
這是給你自由的選擇。
This is the choice
that gives you your freedom.
- 我通知了警察。
- 你的家人還是你的兄弟？
- I alerted the cops.
- Your family or your brother?
好的，我們已經知道你要選擇什麼了。
Okay, we already know
what you're gonna choose.
正確的？ 看看他對你做了什麼。
Right? Look what he's done to you.
他把你帶到你必須殺死的賭徒那裡。
He brought you to the bookie
that you had to kill.
他……他讓你……搶劫銀行。
He... he got you to... to Rob banks.
他教你如何開槍。 就是那個人。
He taught you how to shoot a gun.
That's the guy.
- 快點。 我們要拯救一個世界。
- 閉嘴！ 閉嘴！
- Hurry it up. We got a world to save.
- Shut the fuck up! Shut the fuck up!
他或你的家人。 一個人必須死。
Him or your family. One has to die.
來吧，凱西。 你他媽的已經做出了決定。
Come on, Casey. You've already
made your fucking decision.
快點。
Come on.
去做就對了！
Just do it!
對不起，伙計。
I'm sorry, man.
- 操，對不起，兄弟。
- 不，不。
- Fuck, I'm sorry, brother.
- No, no.
- 我很抱歉。
- 不，不，不，不，不，不！
- I'm so sorry.
- No, no, no, no, no, no!
他媽的。
Fuck.
我很抱歉，但我必須看到。
I'm sorry, but I had to see.
好吧，操你媽的，伙計。
Well, fuck you, man.
你他媽的有病。
You sick fuck.
你真的扣動了扳機？
You actually pulled the trigger?
我必須確定。
I had to know for sure.
你是一個真正的信徒！
You are a true believer!
我知道你有它。
I knew you had it in you.
我為你感到驕傲。
I am so goddamn proud of you.
哦，凱西。 我的男人
Oh, Casey. My man.
你們他媽的人怎麼了？
What's wrong with you fucking people?
看，我今天早上醒來我想
Look, I woke up this morning
andlthought
“我的上帝，除了一件事，我擁有了我生命中所需要的一切。”
"my god, I have everything
I need in my life except one thing."
是啊，那是什麼？ 你他媽的理智？
Yeah, what's that?
Your fucking sanity?
哦，他媽的。
Oh, fuck.
你最後一次睡覺是什麼時候？
When was the last time you slept?
我在休息室抓了一個小時。 我們從騎士那裡得到什麼消息了嗎？
I caught an hour in the break room.
We get any word from knight?
他現在可能已經在去阿根廷的路上了。
He's probably halfway to Argentina by now.
不，他不會逃避戰鬥。
Nah, he wouldn't run from a fight.
不，你想往他最壞的方面想，
Nah, you wanna think the worst of him,
- 但他會在適當的時候出現。
- 不。
- but he'll be there when the time comes.
- No.
你知道，僅僅因為你不想發生某事並不意味著它不會發生。
You know, just because you don't want
something to happen
doesn't mean it won't.
我是單身母親，菲茨。
I'm a single mother, Fitz.
我很清楚制定計劃和讓上帝干涉。
I'm well aware of making plans
and having god interfere.
看在我的城市裡，你已經很生氣了，毫無權限地亂來……
Seeing as how you're already pissed off
and messing around
in my city without authority...
什麼？
What?
- 凱西羅茲。
- 那麼他呢？
- Casey rhodes.
- What about him?
他在越獄期間與康蘭一起出局。
He busted out with conlan
during the jailbreak.
打電話給他的妻子。 她和我們達成了協議。
Called his wife.
She cut a deal with us.
你和那個讓我坐在這該死的椅子上的人達成協議？
You cut a deal with the man who put me
in this fucking chair?
我希望我的城市安全。
I want my city to be safe.
這是達到目的的手段。
It's a means to an end.
你在 conlan 上找到什麼了嗎？
You find anything on conlan?
這傢伙說話的樣子就好像他要完成歷史上最大的搶劫一樣。
The guy's talking like he's about
to pull off the biggest heist in history.
你看，我一直在對潛在目標進行一些研究。
Look, I've been doing some research
on potential targets.
好的？ 而現在，記錄是 97 年的卡利卡車工作。
Okay? And right now, the record
is the Cali truck job in '97.
收入超過 3000 萬。
The take was over 30 mil.
嗯嗯。
Mm-mmm.
最大的搶劫案發生在 75 年。
Biggest heist was in '75.
八個人襲擊了暴徒擁有的一家秘密銀行。
Eight guys hit a secret bank
owned by the mob.
秘密銀行？
A secret bank?
康蘭可能瘋了，但他知道最好不要惹這些家庭。
Conlan may be crazy, but he knows better
than to mess with the families.
- 是的。
- 看，休息一下。
- Yeah.
- Look, get some rest.
奈特會在某個時候回來。
Knight will be back at some point.
說到魔鬼。
Speak of the devil.
他們想讓我值班。 你相信嗎？
They wanna put me on desk duty.
Can you believe that?
- 可能是最好的。
- 打擾一下？
- Probably for the best.
- Excuse me?
為什麼，你認為如果一個人跑上一段樓梯，我就抓不住他？
Why, do you think if a guy runs up
a flight of stairs, I can't catch him?
哦，你就是充滿了聖誕精神，不是嗎？
Oh, you're just
full of Christmas spirit, aren't you, huh?
你這個老混蛋。
You old bastard.
看，遊戲變了，我的兄弟。
See, the games have changed,
my brother.
沒有更多的規則。 沒有更多的代碼。
There's no more rules.
There's no more codes.
遊戲變了。
The game has changed.
是的，康蘭不是人。
Yeah, conlan isn't human.
看，船長和市長說話了。 我和市長談過。
Look, the captain spoke to the mayor.
I spoke to the mayor.
他……他的辦公桌上有這個行程。
He... he had this itinerary on his desk.
某種會議召開地點，我不知道，wooddrake 古董什麼的。
Some kind of meeting set up at,
I don't know,
wooddrake antiques or something.
你能相信那個狗屎嗎？
Can you believe that shit?
當他的城市被一個瘋子圍攻時，那個傢伙正在外出購物。
That guy is out shopping while his city
is under siege from a madman.
你想听些瘋狂的事嗎？
You wanna hear something else crazy?
羅德正在和船長達成交易，爸爸會去爭取的。
Rhodes is cutting a deal with the captain,
and the da is gonna go for it.
絕望的時候。
Desperate times.
老天，如果我他媽的得到羅得島的手，
Christ, if I get
my fucking hands on rhodes,
我要把我的槍對准他的屁股，扣動扳機。
I'm gonna put my gun up his ass,
pull the trigger.
耶穌基督。
Jesus Christ.
你不能停止想他，是嗎？
You can't stop thinking
about him, can you?
忘了這件事，然後回到洛杉磯。
Just forget about this
and come back to la.
他們查你的物證為零。
They have zero physical evidence
to look you up.
你的女兒想你了。 基督，我想念你。
Your daughter misses you.
Christ, I miss you.
你知道 Macey 給我帶來了多少麻煩嗎？
Do you know how much shit
Macey is giving me for even being here?
過年前沒離婚就走運了。
I'll be lucky if I'm not divorced
before new year's.
我就是我。
I am who I am.
好的。 你知道嗎？ 不要聽我說。
Okay, fine. You know what?
Don't listen to me.
但康蘭與其他罪犯不同。
But conlan isn't like any other criminal.
不要讓 conlan 像 winna 那樣影響你。
Don't let conlan get to you like winna.
你永遠不會回來。
You'll never come back.
- 好吧，你錯了。
- 不，我是你的朋友。
- Well, you're wrong.
- No, I'm your friend.
你救了我的命比我吃熱飯的次數還多，我覺得是時候該還債了。
You've saved my life more times
than I've had hot meals,
and I feel like it's time
for me to repay the debt.
好吧，如果康蘭殺了我，那就這樣吧。
Well, if conlan kills me, then so be it.
騎士，我...
Knight, I...
你知道嗎？ 你他媽的讓我變得多愁善感。
And you know what? Fuck you
for making me all sentimental.
剛回家。
Just come home.
不要……不要因為追逐怪物而變成怪物。
Don't... don't turn into a monster
by chasing a monster.
好的？ 這就是我要問的。
Okay? That's all I ask.
只說恩典，我很快就到。
Just say grace and I'll be there soon.
不要那麼戲劇化。
Don't be so dramatic.
當孩子們看到我送給他們的禮物時，他們不會在意我錯過了晚餐。
The kids aren't gonna care
that I missed dinner
when they see the presents I got them.
- 何。
- 好的。
- Ho.
- Okay.
杰羅姆，開車。
Jerome, drive.
媽的。
Oh, shit.
康蘭說我會倖免。
Conlan said I would be spared.
- 他直視著我的眼睛...
- 真的嗎？
- He looked me right in the eye...
- Really?
因為他告訴我要吃富人。
'Cause he told me to eat the rich.
想知道他是不是字面上的意思。
Wonder if he was meaning that literally.
我告訴康蘭，這個城市的每家銀行都在哪裡整合其貴重物品。
I told conlan where every bank
in this city
was consolidating its valuables.
- 我們達成了協議。
- 毫米。
- We made a deal.
- Mm.
好吧，他派我去重新談判。
Well, he sent me to renegotiate.
你見過我兒子嗎？ 我的兒子在哪裡？
Have you seen my son?
Where's my son?
你見過...
Have you seen...
男孩，讓你的屁股過來。
Boy, get your ass over here.
會想念我的 Ted 演講。
Gonna miss my Ted talk.
現在，我知道康蘭是個瘋子。
Now, I know conlan
is a mad son of a bitch.
但所有偉大的都是。
But all the great ones are.
那個人向我展示了真相。
That man has shown me the truth.
我們每個人都被系統虐待、利用。
Every one of us has been abused,
used by the system.
他們奪走了我們的時間，我們的生命。
They have taken our time, our life.
他們把我們關在籠子裡，因為 1% 的人每天都會犯下這些罪行。
They have put us in cages for crimes
that the 1% commit every day.
這座城市屬於我們。
This city belongs to us.
它是我們的，而且一直是我們的！
It is ours, and it always has been ours!
現在是讓每個人都看到光明的時候了。
And now it's time to make
everybody see the light.
計劃很簡單。
The plan is simple.
多虧了我們這裡的新兄弟，市長才會讓我們進去。
Thanks to our new brother here,
the mayor will let us in.
我們將從那裡開始。
And we'll take it from there.
沒有囚犯，沒有倖存者。
No prisoners, no survivors.
你們中有些人不會成功。
Some of you won't make it out.
但是在你們倒下的身體上，我們將建立這個偉大運動的基礎。
But upon your fallen bodies, we will build
the foundation of this great movement.
多年後的某一天，當你老了，躺在病床上，你會抬頭看看你所愛的人
One day, many years from now,
when you're old, lying in your deathbed,
you'll look up at your loved ones
有一瞬間會在你的記憶中閃過。
and one moment
will flash before your memory.
這天。
This day.
這一刻的偉大。
This moment of greatness.
你們是我的兄弟，我為你們感到驕傲。
You're my brothers,
and I'm proud of you.
嘿。
Hey.
你來找我，記得嗎？
You came to me, remember?
你說你爸壓著你，他一腳踩在你身上，把你按在地上，這樣他才能爬起來。
You said your father held you down,
he put his foot on you
現在呢？
and pushed you to the ground,
so he could rise up. And now what?
現在你一個人嗎？ 不，你是我們中的一員。
Now you're alone?
No, you're one of us.
你是我們家庭的一員。 你現在是一個真正的家庭。
You're part of our family.
You're in a real family now.
我以你為榮。 你做出了正確的選擇。
I'm proud of you.
You made the right choice.
因為我們將永遠在您身邊。
'Cause we will always be there for you.
像對待彼此一樣對待他。 他現在是我們中的一員。
Treat him the way you treat each other.
He's one of us now.
你明白了。
You got this.
你現在和我們在一起，你會完全按照我們說的去做。
You're with us now,
and you will do exactly as we say.
當我告訴你時你說。
You speak when I tell you.
當我告訴你時，你會跳起來。
You jump when I tell you.
我一說你就開槍。
You shoot when I tell you.
現在穿好衣服，婊子。
Now get dressed, bitch.
J“寂靜的夜晚j”
J“ silent night j“
j“聖夜我”
j“ holy night I“
j“一切都很平靜j“
j“ all is calm j“
我“一切都是光明的 j”
I“ and all is bright j"
j“圍繞著處女母子我“
j“ round yon virgin mother and child I“
j“聖嬰如此溫柔溫和 j”
j“ holy infant so tender and mild j"
j“睡在天堂般的和平中 j“
j“ sleep in heavenly peace j“
j“寂靜的夜晚j“
j“ silent night j“
j“聖夜我”
j“ holy night I“
j“牧羊人地震 j“
j“ Shepherds quake j“
j“在視線j”
j“ at the sight j”
j“從你聖潔的臉上發出光芒四射的夢想 j”
j“ radiant dreams from thy holy face j"
騎士兄弟。
Brother knight.
聽說你一直在追我
I hear you've been chasing me.
有什麼事？
What's the matter?
你怎麼還沒抓到我？ 你變老了嗎？
Why haven't you caught me yet?
You growing old?
慢下來？
Slowing down?
- 是的。 交通。
- 交通哦！
- Yeah. Traffic.
- Traffic, oh!
說謊者。 上帝，我多麼討厭說謊者。
Liar. God, how I hate liars.
這個城市到處都是騙子、偽君子和小偷。
This city is full of liars,
hypocrites and thieves.
- 羅德？
- 哦耶。
- Rhodes?
- Oh, yeah.
他看到了大局。
He sees the big picture.
大解脫。
The great liberation.
他現在是其中的一部分。
He's a part of it now.
我就像北極星，為這個寒冷的聖誕夜指引方向。
I'm like the north star, guiding the way
through this cold Christmas night.
他像飛馬一樣騎在我身邊。
And he's riding alongside
of me like Pegasus.
而他想要的一切...
And all he wants...
他只想和家人在一起。
All he wants is to be with his family.
他正在成為我們中的一員。
He's becoming one of us.
當他成為保羅時，他就像掃羅一樣，進化成更大更好的東西。
He's like Saul when he became Paul,
evolving into something bigger and better.
- 我很自豪。
- 我從沒說過他很聰明。
- I'm so proud.
- I never said he was smart.
我想你，詹姆斯。
I miss you, James.
我願意。 我想念我們。
I do. I miss us.
哦，我們在一起會很棒。
Oh, we would have been great together.
太糟糕了。
It's too bad.
沒有更多的牛仔警察，他們殺死了我們所有的英雄。
There are no more cowboy cops,
and they've killed all our heroes.
只有我們。
It's just us.
你以為我只是在搶劫銀行，炸毀銀行？
You think I'm just robbing banks
and blowing up banks?
遠不止於此。
It's so much more than that.
你看不到大局。
You don't see the big picture.
聖誕節是關於團聚的。
Christmas is about togetherness.
這不是所有這些物質狗屎。 誰在乎？
It's not all this material shit.
Who cares?
玩具和小工具，它們沒有任何意義。
Toys and gadgets,
they don't mean anything.
希望。
Hope.
希望是最重要的，希望是一件危險的事情。
Hope is all that matters,
and hope is a dangerous thing.
最後一次，詹姆斯。
One last time, James.
- 加入我。
- 有酒嗎？
- Join me.
- Got any booze?
是的。
Yeah.
市長剛剛告訴我他把好東西放在哪裡了。
The mayor just told me where
he's keeping the good stuff.
今晚過後，我要醉到情人節。
After tonight, I'm gonna stay drunk
until Valentine's day.
對於這裡的酗酒者來說，這裡就像諾克斯堡。
It's gonna be like fort Knox
for alcoholics over here.
加入我。
Join me.
在我改變世界之前的最後機會。
Last chance before I change the world.
這只會在我們中的一個人死去時結束。
This only ends when one of us is dead.
如果你堅持。
If you insist.
讓我們繼續前進！
Let's move!
騎士兄弟，改變需要犧牲。
Brother knight, change takes sacrifice.
市長剛剛告訴我他把好東西放在哪裡了。
The mayor just told me
where he's keeping the good stuff.
某種會議召開地點，我不知道，wooddrake 古董什麼的。
Some kind of meeting set up at,
I don't know,
wooddrake antiques or something.
好了，吃飽了。
All right, chow's up.
感謝您在聖誕節來到這裡。
Thank you for being here
on Christmas day.
嗯，很高興知道你記得我的電話號碼。
Well, it's nice to know
you remembered my number.
我知道他要打哪裡。
I know where he's gonna hit.
伍德雷克古董。
Wooddrake antiques.
它是 1% 的前線。
It's a front for the 1%.
他沒有搶銀行。
He wasn't robbing banks.
他在製造恐懼。
He was creating fear.
他讓每個人都把貴重物品放在一個地方。
He made everyone put their valuables
in one place.
沒有理由去搶一百家銀行，你知道的，只搶一家。
There's no reason to Rob a hundred banks
when you can just, you know, Rob one.
好吧，偵探，這真是該死的好工作。
Well, that's some damn fine work,
detective.
別動。 讓我告訴乳木果。
Don't move. Let me tell shea.
你一個人抓不到康蘭。 他沒有什麼可失去的。
You can't catch conlan alone.
He's got nothing to lose.
如果我能救一個人，那也是值得的。
If I can save just one person,
it's worth it.
這就是我所做的。
That's what I do.
餵，騎士，不要一個人進去。
Hey, knight, don't go in there alone.
騎士……騎士！
Kni... knight!
拉屎。
Shit.
對不起。
I'm sorry.
他有我的兒子。
He has my son.
他們給我兒子洗腦。
They brainwashed my son.
他是自願來的。
He came willingly.
你違背了諾言，康蘭。
You broke your promise, conlan.
聽這位政治家給我們講講失信。
Listen to the politician give us lectures
on broken promises.
我唯一的承諾是對全能者本人的承諾。
The only promise I made was
to the almighty himself.
我答應他讓天堂充滿新鮮的靈魂。
I promised him to keep heaven
full of fresh souls.
所以這裡的羅德最好還是熱心支持他，或者他漂亮的妻子莉莉，還有那個可愛的女兒克拉拉，
So rhodes here better be
enthusiastic in his support,
or his beautiful wife, Lily,
and that sweet daughter, Clara,
永遠不會醒來打開他們的禮物...
are never gonna wake up
to open their presents on...
拜託，康蘭。 我們說好的。
Please, conlan. We had a deal.
我可以給你任何你想要的。
I can give you anything you want.
- 我可以給你城市的鑰匙。
- 城市的鑰匙？
- I can give you the keys to the city.
- The keys to the city?
真的嗎？ 你能給我城市的鑰匙嗎？
Really? You can give me
the keys to the city?
當鑰匙保管員就在我的貨車裡時，我就不需要城市的鑰匙了。
I don't need the keys to the city
when I have the keeper of the keys
right here in my Van.
不是這樣的。 這太遠了。
Not like this. This is too far.
- 你會讓這座城市倒退 50 年。
- 不，不，不，我的兄弟。
- You're gonna set the city back 50 years.
- No, no, no, my brother.
我將推動這座城市走向未來。
I'm going to propel
the city into the future.
我們要揭露精英階層的黑暗秘密。
We're gonna expose
the dark secrets of the elite.
所以鎖定並加載，兄弟們。 我們有工作要做。
So lock and load, brothers.
We got a job to do.
微笑，市長。 今天是聖誕節。
Smile, mayor. It's Christmas.
讓遊戲開始。
Let the games begin.
要用鮮血裝飾大廳，混蛋。 我們走吧。
Gonna deck the halls with blood,
motherfuckers. Let's go.
其他人就位。
The other guys are in position.
我需要提款。
I need to make a withdrawal.
怎麼樣了？
How's it going?
你現在可以進來了。
You can come in now.
呃呃，你別動。
Uh-uh, don't you move.
讓他們擁有一切！
Let them have everything!
只要給他們他們想要的！
Just give them what they want!
我們不必被給予任何東西。
We don't have to be given anything.
我們要帶走一切。
We're gonna take everything.
我們開始這個派對吧。
Let's get this party started.
呵呵。 呵呵。 呵呵。 呵呵。 呵呵。
Ho. Ho. Ho. Ho. Ho.
呵呵。 呵呵。 呵呵。 呵呵。
Ho. Ho. Ho. Ho.
呵呵。 呵呵。 呵呵。
Ho. Ho. Ho.
叮噹聲，婊子們。
Jingle on this, bitches.
請不要開槍。 我只是個瞭望員。
Please, don't shoot. I'm just the lookout.
從來不應該是這樣的。
It was never supposed to be like this.
康蘭說我們正在開始一場革命。
Conlan said we were starting a revolution.
裡面有幾個？
How many in there?
十，十五。我不知道。
Ten, 15. I don't know.
但它們都是缺點。 鐵桿。
But they're all cons. Hardcore.
我只是想變得強硬。
I just wanted to be tough.
我打賭你現在很堅強。
I bet you're tough now.
滾開
Fuck off.
呵呵。 呵呵。 呵呵。 呵呵。
Ho. Ho. Ho. Ho.
別動。
Don't move.
移動它。
Move it.
保持冷靜，聖誕老人。
Stay frosty, santas.
打開金庫。
Open the vault.
移動！
Move!
哦。 聖誕快樂，我的兄弟們。
Oh. Merry Christmas, my brothers.
是時候收穫忠誠的回報了。
Time to reap the rewards of your loyalty.
這一切只是為了偷東西？
All this just to steal some shit?
不。
No.
- 這是關於重新啟動系統。
- 哦，廢話。
- This is about rebooting the system.
- Oh, bullshit.
廢話，伙計。 你不過是個小偷。
Bullshit, man. You're nothing but a thief.
不，我不是小偷。
No. I'm no thief.
我只是一個玩弄造就我的系統的人。
I'm just a man who played
the system that made me.
拉屎。
Shit.
你們中的一部分相信這個使命。
Part of you believes in this mission.
我可以從你的眼睛裡看到它。
I can see it in your eyes right there.
看這個。 看看這些財富。
Look at this. Look at these riches.
我們可以以此推翻政府。
We can overthrow governments with this.
我們可以實現大解脫。
We can bring about the great liberation.
這是人類不破裂的開始。
This is the beginning
of the unbreaking of humanity.
我父親教我修理壞掉的東西。
My father taught me to fix what's broken.
你父親是個混蛋。
Your father was a cuck.
有了深層政府的球...
With the deep state's balls...
撓他的扁桃體。
Tickling his tonsils.
我父親教我如果你不能改變世界...
My father taught me
that if you can't change the world...
讓它屈服。
Bring it to its knees.
我們是如此接近。 很近。
We are so close. So close.
難道你不明白嗎？
Don't you understand?
他們用虛假的戰爭殺死了我的兒子。
They killed my son
with their fake wars.
在他們對你的孩子這樣做之前，我會結束他們。
I will end them before
they do that to your child.
我正在為你做這件事。
I'm doing this for you.
幫助我，我求求你。
Help me, I beg you.
聽我說。 聽我說。
Listen to me. Listen to me.
聽我說。
Listen to me.
聖誕節是關於團聚的。
Christmas is about togetherness.
我需要你。
I need you.
我需要你幫助這些人把戰利品拿出來。
I need you to help these men
bring out that loot.
這樣做，我向馬槽裡的嬰兒發誓，我會讓你的家人離開。
Do that, and I swear on the baby
in the manger, I will let your family go.
我們四分鐘後離開這裡，聖誕老人。
We're out of here in four minutes, santas.
你做得很好。
You did good.
愚蠢的精英們認為他們可以把珍珠藏在一家倒閉的銀行里。
Stupid-ass elites think they can hide
their pearls in a closed-down bank.
是的，一旦它被圍起來，這個狗屎至少要有九位數。
Yeah, this shit got to be
at least nine figures once it's fenced.
金錢只是記分的一種方式。
Money is just a way of keeping score.
我們將重新分配世界的財富。
We'll redistribute the wealth
of the world.
我們做到了，達容。
We did it, dajon.
好的，我完成了。
Okay, I'm done.
- 當我說你完成時你就完成了。
- 不不不不。
- You're done when I say you're done.
- No, no, no, no.
我幫你拿了你那該死的戰爭寶箱，好吧...
I helped you get your little
fucking war chest thing, okay...
- 這不是談判！
- 我他媽的完了！
- This is not a negotiation!
- I'm fucking done!
把你他媽的手從我身上拿開。
Get your fucking hands off me.
我有你的妻子 我有你的女兒
I have your wife. I have your daughter.
你現在是我們中的一員了。
You're one of us now.
像它一樣。
Act like it.
嘿！ 你是誰？
Hey! Who are you?
什麼……哦，他媽的！ 他媽的！ 他媽的！ 他媽的！ 他媽的！
What the... oh, fuck!
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
那他媽的是什麼？ 那是手榴彈嗎？
What the fuck is that?
Is that a grenade?
他媽的，他媽的，他媽的！ 它去哪兒了？ 它去哪兒了？
Fuck, fuck, fuck! Where did it go?
Where did it go?
快點他媽的。 他在這裡！
Hurry the fuck up. He's here!
來吧，走吧！ 來吧，走吧！
Come on, go! Come on, go!
他媽的就是這些？
The fuck is all that?
這他媽的是什麼？ 你給他們小費？
What the fuck is all that?
You tip 'em off?
他在這裡。
He's here.
你躲在哪裡，偵探？
Where are you hiding, detective?
我能聞到你的味道。
I can smell you.
恐懼無處不在，伙計。
Fear everywhere, buddy.
帥氣的禿頭魔王，出來玩吧。
You handsome bald devil,
come out and play.
哈哈哈。
Ho, ho, ho.
你好，偵探。
Hello, detective.
平安夜沒有什麼更好的事可做？
Nothing better to do on Christmas Eve?
這對我來說已經很好了。
This is as good as it gets for me.
好吧，有像我們這樣的朋友，誰還需要家人呢？
Well, with friends like us,
who needs family?
我對嗎？
Am I right?
- 這就是它的發展方向。
- 我會告訴你怎麼做。
- This is how it's gonna go.
- I'll tell you how.
我要把聖誕樹塞到你屁股上……
I'm gonna shove a Christmas tree
up your ass...
並將其點燃。
And set it on fire.
我的屁股上有一棵聖誕樹？
A Christmas tree up my ass?
一路走來。
All the way.
好吧好吧。 你比我想像的更變態，偵探。
Okay, okay. You're even kinkier
than I thought, detective.
但我喜歡那樣。 沒有前戲，好嗎？
But I like that. No foreplay, okay?
你要確保我們安全無恙地離開這裡。
You're gonna make sure
we walk out of here free and clear.
為什麼？ 因為你拿槍指著他的頭？
Why? Because you have
a gun to his head?
我他媽的在乎嗎？ 射他。
The fuck do I care? Shoot him.
什麼？
What?
你射殺了我的搭檔。
You shot my partner.
看到我在這里處理什麼了嗎？
See what I'm dealing with here?
他把你賣到河上游了，羅茲。
He sold you up the river, rhodes.
你對他來說毫無意義。
You mean nothing to him.
還不如什麼都沒有。
Less than nothing.
還不如什麼都沒有。 哇。 你很冷，偵探。
Less than nothing. Wow.
You're cold, detective.
哇。
Wow.
Dajon，你忘了給我買聖誕禮物。
Dajon, you forgot to get me
a Christmas present.
我想要這個混蛋的腦袋在我的襪子裡，拜託。
I would like this motherfucker's head
in my stocking, please.
有人會殺了他嗎？
Would someone just kill him?
偵探騎士，你的聖誕精神在哪裡？
Where is your Christmas spirit,
detective knight?
Dajon，別胡鬧了。 你讓那個漂亮男孩踢你的屁股？
Dajon, quit fucking around.
You let that pretty boy kick your ass?
我把你訓練得比那更好，你這個小賤人。
I trained you better than that,
you little pussy.
我來了，老大！
I'm coming, boss!
他媽的。
Fuck.
呃哦。
Uh-oh.
聽起來聖誕老人沒有給你足夠的彈藥來參加這個派對。
Sounds like Santa claus didn't give you
enough ammunition for this party.
你不用擔心。
Don't you worry.
康蘭神父子彈綽綽有餘，分享給大家。
Father conlan has more than enough bullets
to share with you.
你又說對了，騎士。 這只會以我們中的一個人死去而告終。
You were right again, knight.
This only ends with one of us dead.
聖誕快樂，混蛋。
Merry Christmas, motherfucker.
你好嗎，兄弟？
How you doing, brother?
你他媽的——哦。
You f—- oh.
哇。
Wow.
沒看到那來。
Didn't see that coming.
我們好嗎？
Are we good?
我的意思是，不是，你知道，很好。
I mean, not, you know, good-good.
但是夠好了嗎？
But good enough?
在我給槍上潤滑油之前，我會給你五秒鐘的時間。
I'm gonna give you five seconds
before I lube up my gun.
這他媽是什麼意思？
What the fuck does that mean?
好吧，我猜你會在四小時內找到答案。
Well, I guess you're gonna
find out in four.
二。
Two.
會沒事的。
It's gonna be okay.
我的天啊。 我的天啊。
Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
會沒事的。 沒關係。
It's gonna be okay. It's okay.
太感謝了。 謝謝你。
Thank you so much. Thank you.
謝謝謝謝。
Thank you, thank you.
亞瑟！
Arthur!
亞瑟，你在哪裡？
Arthur, where are you?
凍結！ 紐約警察局！
Freeze! NYPD!
放下它！ 我們可以看到它們的手。
Put it down! Hands where we can see them.
我在找我的兒子。 亞瑟·瓦塞蒂。
I'm looking for my son. Arthur vassetti.
請幫我找到我的兒子
Please, help me find my son.
我的兒子在哪裡？
Where is my son?
我兒子的名字叫亞瑟瓦塞蒂。
My son's name is Arthur vassetti.
瑞奇康蘭帶走了我的兒子！
Ricky conlan took my son!
康蘭在教堂見過你的兒子嗎？
Did conlan
meet your son at church?
我的兒子亞瑟在哪裡？
Where's my son, Arthur?
你為康蘭工作了多久？
How long were
you working for conlan?
把他關起來！ 把他關起來！
Lock him up! Lock him up!
瑞奇康蘭有我的兒子。
Ricky conlan has my son.
找到我的兒子！
Find my son!
你是不斷給予的禮物。
You're the gift that keeps on giving.
你贏了。
You win.
不要讓他們把我關在籠子裡。
Don't let them put me in a cage.
我不會回去的。
I'm not going back.
殺我。
Kill me.
做吧。
Do it.
聖誕快樂，混蛋。
Merry Christmas, motherfucker.
吼！
Ho!
國家呼籲立場偵探菲茨杰拉德。
The state calls
to the stand detective Fitzgerald.
很高興再次見到你站起來，菲茨。
Good to see you
on your feet again, Fitz.
任何能讓你開心的事，梅森。
Anything to make you happy, Mason.
你能為我們節省大量時間並告訴我們關於你伴侶的真實情況如何？
How about you save us all a bunch of time
and tell us the real truth
about your partner?
哦，我從哪裡開始呢？
Oh, where do I begin?
奈特因紐約市的非同尋常事件而被免罪，檢察官缺乏指控他所需的證據
Knight was cleared for the extraordinary
events in New York City
and the prosecutor lacks the evidence
he needs to charge him
因為謀殺了一個傑里·利奇，事實上，這並不能使那個人無罪。
for the murder of one Jerry leach
which, ipso facto,
does not make that guy innocent.
事實上？
Ipso facto?
誰在乎？
Who gives a fuck?
沒有人為 Jerry Leach 哭泣。
No one's crying for Jerry leach.
這名男子是一名被定罪的殺人犯，他因技術問題而下車。
The man was a convicted murderer
who got off on a technicality.
如果騎士殺了他，那只是為了在他傷害別人之前阻止他。
If knight killed him,
it was only to stop him
before he hurt someone else.
偵探，騎士身陷囹圄還是身披徽章，這個世界更安全嗎？
Detective, is the world a safer place
with knight behind bars
or behind a badge?
老實說，我從哪裡開始？
Honestly, where do I begin?
他喜怒無常，沒有條理，他開得很快，整天都在胡說八道。
He's moody, disorganized,
he drives fast, talks shit all day.
他是一個工作狂。
He's a workaholic.
我曾經抓到他在停車場教我的大兒子做電子剎車轉彎。
I once caught him teaching my eldest son
to do e-brake turns in a parking lot.
好的？ 我的兒子山姆九歲。 九歲。
Okay? My son Sam is nine.
Nine years old.
而且他不認為自己做錯了什麼。
And he didn't think that
he was doing anything wrong.
他還沒有收到支票，在我們成為合夥人的八年裡一次也沒有。
He has yet to pick up a check,
not once in the eight years
that we've been partners.
我們只能說這傢伙是個混蛋。
Let's just say this guy is an asshole.
但被人喜歡不是他的工作。
But it's not his job to be liked.
這個人的經驗比部門裡其他人的總和還多。
This man has more experience
than the rest of the guys
in the department combined.
他是第一個到場的人。 他是第一個進門的人。
He's the first man on the scene.
He's the first man through the door.
這個人是警察。
This guy is a cop.
在徽章背後有 James Knight，我們都更加安全。
And we are all much safer
with James knight behind the badge.
在聽取了兩打證詞、評估受害人影響陳述和他過去的案件後，
After hearing
two dozen testimonies,
assessing victim impact statements
and his past cases,
該部門建議讓詹姆斯·奈特復職，立即生效。
the department recommends
that James knight
be reinstated effective immediately.
恭喜你，偵探。
Congratulations, detective.